Guide to the Cynthia Harrison feminist document collection, 1921-2008 MS1005.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Manuscript research, 1923-1988; Series 8 (Box 24, Box 25, Box 37, Box 28, Box 29, Box 26, Box 27, Box 32, Box 33, Box 30, Box 31, Box 35, Box 34, Box 36)
  - PCSW Committees SIT [3/5], 1963; Series 8 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - PCSW Committees SIT [4/5], 1963-1964; Series 8 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - PCSW Committees SIT [5/5], Undated; Series 8 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - PCSW Effectiveness, 1961-1965; Series 8 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - PCSW Executive Commission on Women pre-1961, 1948-1957; Series 8 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - PCSW Formation, 1960-1962; Series 8 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - PCSW: Four Consultations Report, 1963 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - PCSW Functioning [1/3], 1961-1962; Series 8 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - PCSW Functioning [2/3], 1962; Series 8 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - PCSW Functioning [3/3], 1963; Series 8 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - PCSW Members, 1961-1979; Series 8 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - PCSW Papers Not Used, 1962-1963; Series 8 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - PCSW Pauli Murray Papers PM SL unprocessed, 1962-1963; Series 8 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - PCSW Report, 1962-1980; Series 8 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - PCSW Staff, 1962; Series 8 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - PCSW Ware Memorandum, 1962-1974; Series 8 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - PCSW 1964 - [1/5], 1963-1964; Series 8 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - PCSW 1964 - [2/5], 1965; Series 8 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - PCSW 1964 - [3/5], 1966; Series 8 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - PCSW 1964 - [4/5], 1967; Series 8 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - PCSW 1964 - [5/5], 1968; Series 8 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Ref. File C.S.C., 1934-1965; Series 8 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Ref. File: Polls Notes, 1949-1967; Series 8 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Reproductive Health Equity Act 1985, Series 8 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Reproductive Rights, 1983-1989; Series 8 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Resources, 1962-1973; Series 8 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - S.3077 1966, 1966 May 23; Series 8 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Social Security, 1950-1979; Series 8 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - State Commissions, 1962-1967; Series 8 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Surnames, 1972-1982; Series 8 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Title IX Background [5/5], 1971-1978; Series 8 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Title IX and Educational Equity, 1972-1979; Series 8 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Truman Background, 1945-1972; Series 8 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - 1936 Tipaldo Case, Series 8 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Will E. Leuchtenburg, 1982; Series 8 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Women Doers, 1963-1968; Series 8 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Women Gneral 1945-1952, 1948-1978; Series 8 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Women General 1960-, 1961-1968; Series 8 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Women in Industry Service WWI, 1918; Series 8 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Women Reporters, 1945-1964; Series 8 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Women's Advocacy Committee on Defense Manpower (to Department of Labor) 1951-2, 1951-1952; Series 8 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Women's Bureau General 1961-63, 1961-1963; Series 8 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Women's Bureau General 1945-1952, 1944-1952; Series 8 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Women's Bureau 1945-1952 Supplementary, 1945-1957; Series 8 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Women's Bureau General [1/2] 1953-1960, 1955-1960; Series 8 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Women's Bureau General [2/2] 1953-1960, 1953-1955; Series 8 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Women's Bureau (WB) General 1964 -, 1964-1968; Series 8 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Women's Bureau Office Files (GCSLW - Conferences), 1965-1968; Series 8 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Women's Bureau - Status Bill - Department of Labor, 1947-1953; Series 8 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Women's Bureau General Pre-1945, 1943-1945; Series 8 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Women's Employment 1945-1960, 1945-1958; Series 8 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Women's Employment 1964 -, 1964-1966; Series 8 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Women's History Readings, Undated; Series 8 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Women's Issues in the News 1976, Series 8 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Women's Junior League Committee 1946-1947, Series 8 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Women's Organizations 1945-1952, 1939-1950; Series 8 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Women's Bureau Legislative Program pre-1945, 1944-1945; Series 8 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Women's Organizations 1953-1960, 1948-1958; Series 8 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Women's Organizations 1961 -, 1961-1965; Series 8 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Women Studies Abstracts, 1972-1979; Series 8 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Women's Studies Bibliography, Undated; Series 8 (Box 37, Folder 15)
- Oral history, 1974-1981; Series 9 (Box 38)
  This series consists of interview transcripts and oral histories from people active in the women's rights movement, including suffragist Alice Paul, Esther Peterson, Catherine East, Dr. Richard A. Lester, Edith Green, Marguerite Rawalt and Maurine Neuberger. Most of the interviews were conducted in the late 1970's to early 1980's.
  - Alice Paul Transcript Notes, 1976; Series 9 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Interviews EG, EP, MN, RL, CE, 1974-1981; Series 9 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Rawalt Oral History, Undated; Series 9 (Box 38, Folder 3)
- Political involvement, 1959-1991; Series 10 (Box 38)
  This series consists of mailings from women political candidates and women's political organizations, party platform reports and analyses, and publications on women's rights legistlation dating largely from the 1980's and early 1990's. These documents are in part a collection of resources accumulated by Harrison, and in part evidence of Harrison's own participation in political activities.
  - Center for American Woman and Politics Fact Sheets, Highlight Brochure, Press Advisory, 1988-1990; Series 10 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - DSCC (Democratic Senatorial Campaign Committee), 1988-1990; Series 10 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - The Democratic Party, 1988-1991; Series 10 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Legislation Affecting the Status of Women, 1959-1983; Series 10 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - National Women's Political Caucus, 1973-1991; Series 10 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Political Campaigns, 1987-1991; Series 10 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Position Paper draft: Women's Issues in the 1984 Campaign, 1983; Series 10 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Women as Leaders, 1989-1991; Series 10 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Women's Campaign Fund, 1986-1990; Series 10 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Women's Vote Project, 1988; Series 10 (Box 38, Folder 13)
- Oversized boxes, 1945-1987; Series 11 (Box 41, Box 39, Box 40)
  This series contains oversized materials relating to the Equal Pay Act, Equal Rights Amendment, Title IX, and the women's rights movement in general dating from the 1940's to the 1980's.
  - Campaign 1960 Includes Platforms, 1956-1963; Series 11 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Equal Pay Act 1961, 1960-1978; Series 11 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Equal Pay Act 1962, 1962-1963; Series 11 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Equal Pay Act 1963, 1963-1967; Series 11 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Equal Pay Act 1963 (Jan-Mar), Series 11 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - ERA 1945-1952 [1/2], 1945-1950; Series 11 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - ERA 1945-1952 [2/2], 1950-1952; Series 11 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - ERA 1953-1960 Supplemental Material, 1952-1960; Series 11 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - ERA 1961-1963, 1961-1977; Series 11 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Esther Peterson Oral History John F. Kennedy Library, 1966-1981; Series 11 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - NOW Formation - Chronology, 1966-1987; Series 11 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - NYRF: New York Radical Feminists Newsletter, 1973 July; Series 11 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Saskatoon Women's Liberation Newsletter, 1973; Series 11 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Title IX Background [1/4], 1963-1968; Series 11 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Title IX Background [2/4], 1965-1966; Series 11 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Title IX Backbround [3/4], 1966-1967; Series 11 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Title IX Background [4/4], 1967-1968; Series 11 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Women's Liberation Newsletter from Winnipeg, 1973 September 4; Series 11 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Women Returning to the Labor Force: A First Report, Women's Bureau Careers Centre Ontario Department of Labor, Undated; Series 11 (Box 41, Folder 6)
- Women's issues resources, 1971-2008; 1989-1996; Series 12
  This series contains publications, newsletters, reports and mailings covering a wide range of women's rights issues and documenting the activities and concerns of feminist organizations in the late 1980's and early 1990's. Harrison's original organization scheme has largely been maintained, with folders on topics ranging from abortion, to work/family balance, to women in the media. Of particular interest are publications commenting on the UN Fourth World Conference on Women, and documents related to the formation in 2005 of GWU's Sexual Harassment Policy.
  - Abortion, 1989-1998; Series 12 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Aging & Older Women's Issues, 1989-2002; Series 12 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Conferences, 1977-1998; Series 12 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Contraception [1/2], 1987-1998; Series 12 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Contraception [2/2], 1986-1996; Series 12 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1998-1999; Series 12 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Courts/Women's Legal Theory [1/4], 1994-1997; Series 12 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Courts/Women's Legal Theory [2/4], 1983; Series 12 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Courts/Women's Legal Theory [3/4], 1977-1994; Series 12 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Courts/Women's Legal Theory [4/4], 1995; Series 12 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Discrimination Against Women, 1973-1997; Series 12 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Economics, 1993-1998; Series 12 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Equal Pay [1/2], 1993-1999; Series 12 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Equal Pay [2/2], 1985-1996; Series 12 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, 1989; Series 12 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Education [1/2], 1973-1998; Series 12 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Education [2/2], 1972-1997; Series 12 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Employment [1/3], 1991-1998; Series 12 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Employment [2/3], 1989-1998; Series 12 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Employment [3/3], 1972-1993; Series 12 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Feminism, 1977-1997; Series 12 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Gay Rights, 1990-1996; Series 12 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Haitian Women's Rights, 1993-1994; Series 12 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Insurance, 1989-1996; Series 12 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - International Women's Rights [1/2], 1993-1997; Series 12 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - International Women's Rights [2/2], 1995-1999; Series 12 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Mailings: DC Area Women's Rights Organizations, 1988-1994; Series 12 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Mailings: Ms Foundation for Women, 1989-1990; Series 12 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Mailings: The Feminist Majority Foundation, 1990-1999; Series 12 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Mailings: National Abortion Rights Action League (NARAL), 1992-1995; Series 12 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Mailings: (NWPC) National Women's Rights Political Caucus, 1989-1998; Series 12 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Mailings: NOW (National Organization for Women), 1981-1999; Series 12 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Mailings: NOW Legal Defense and Education Fund, 1991-1992; Series 12 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Mailings: Other Women's Rights Organizations, 1989-1995; Series 12 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Mailings: Planned Parenthood, 1990-1998; Series 12 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Mailings: The Women's Freedom Network Newsletter, 1994-1998; Series 12 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Mailings: Women's Issues Network, 1992; Series 12 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Mailings: Women's Legal Defense Fund/National Partnership for Women & Families, 1991-1998; Series 12 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - National Women's Health Network, 1990-1994; Series 12 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Nursing, 1989-1992; Series 12 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Parental Leave, 1989-1995; Series 12 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Racial Issues, 1986-1995; Series 12 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Reports of the National Advisory Council on Women's Educational Programs, 1976-1982; Series 12 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Sexual Harassment, 1995-1997; Series 12 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Sexual Harassment Policy at GW, 2005; Series 12 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - UN Convention on the Elimination of all Forms of Discrimination Against Women, 1980-1997; Series 12 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - UN Fourth World Conference on Women - Beijing, China, 1994-1997; Series 12 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Violence Against Women, 1989-2008; Series 12 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Welfare, 1996-2002; Series 12 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Women in Government & at the Polls, 1989-1998; Series 12 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Women's Health [1/2], 1991-1999; Series 12 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Women's Health [2/2], 1990-1997; Series 12 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Women in History [1/2], 1976-1999; Series 12 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Women in History [2/2], 1988-1999; Series 12 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Women in Media, 1991-1996; Series 12 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Women in the Military, 1991-1999; Series 12 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - The Women's Movement, 1996; Series 12 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Women in Sports, 1996; Series 12 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Women's Studies [1/3], 1989-1996; Series 12 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Women's Studies [2/3], 1971; Series 12 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Women's Studies [3/3], 1976; Series 12 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Work/Family Balance, 1987-1999; Series 12 (Box 48, Folder 10)